in lesson one we'll be covering models prompts and parsers so models refers to the language models
underpinning a lot of it prompts refers to the the style of creating inputs to pass into the
models and then parsers is on the opposite end it's it involves taking the output of these models
and parsing it into a more structured format so that you can do things downstream with it
yep so when you build a application using an lm they'll often be reusable models we have repeatedly
prompted model parsers outputs and so launching gives an easy set of abstractions to do this type
of operation so with that let's jump in and take a look at models prompts and parsers so to get
started here's a little bit of starter code i'm going to import os import openai and load my openai
secret key um the openai library is already installed in my jupyten notebook environment
if you're running this locally and you don't have openai installed yet you might need to
run that uh bank pip install openai but i'm not going to do that here
and then here's a helper function this is actually um very similar to the helper function that you might
have seen in the chat gpt prompt engineering for developers course that i offered together with
openai's user forfeit and so with this helper function you can say get to completion on um what is one plus
one and this will call chat gpt or technically the model gpt 3.5 turbo to give you an answer back like
this now to motivate the line chain abstractions for model prompts and pauses um let's say you get an
email from a customer in a language other than english um in order to make sure this is accessible the
other language i'm going to use is the english pirate language when it comes to this are i'd be fuming
that me blend the lid flew off and splattered my kitchen walls with smoothie and to make matters worse
the warranty don't cover the cost of cleaning up me kitchen i need your help right now matey and so what we
will do is ask this olm to translate the text to american english in a calm and respectful tone
so i'm going to set style to american english in a calm and respectful tone
and so in order to actually accomplish this if you've seen a little bit of prompting before
i'm going to specify the prompt using an f string with the instructions translate the text that is delimited by
by triple backticks into style that is style and then plug in these two styles and so this generates
a prompt that says translate the text and so on i encourage you to pause the video and run the code
and also try modifying the prompt to see if you can get a different output
you can then um prompt the large language model to get a response
let's see what the response is it says translated the english pirate's message into this very polite
i'm really frustrated that my blender lid flew off and made a mess of my kitchen walls with smoothie and so
on um i could really use your help right now my friend that sounds very nice so if you have different
customers writing reviews in different languages not just english pirate but french german japanese and so
on you can imagine having to generate a whole sequence of prompts to generate such translations
let's look at how we can do this in a more convenient way using langchain
i'm going to import chat openai this is language abstraction for the chat gpt
api endpoint and so if i then set chat equals chat openai and look like chat is it creates this object
as follows that uses the chat gpt model which is also called gpt 3.5 turbo
when i'm building applications one thing i will often do is set the temperature parameter to be equal to
zero so the default temperature is 0.7 but let me actually redo that with temperature
equals 0.0 and now the temperature is set to zero to make this output a little bit less random
and now let me define the template string as follows translate the text delimited by
triple tactics into style that is style and then here's the text and to repeatedly reuse this template
let's import langchain's chat prompt template and then let me create the prompt template using that
template string that we just wrote above
from the prompt template you can actually extract the original prompt and it realizes that this prompt
the prompt has two input variables the style and the text which were shown here with the curly braces
and here is the original template as well that we had specified
and in fact to print this out it realizes it has two input variables style and text now let's specify the style this is a style that i want the customer message to be translated to so i'm going to call this customer style
and here's my same customer email as before and now
if i create customer messages this will generate
the prompt and will pass this a large language more than a minute to get a response so if you want to
look at the types the custom message is actually a list and if you look at
the first element of the list this is more or less that prompts that you would expect this to be creating
lastly let's pass this prompt to the lm so i'm going to call chat which we had said earlier
as a reference to the open ai chat gpd endpoint and
if we print out the customer responses content then it gives you back um this
text translated from english pirate to polite american english and of course you can imagine other use
cases where the customer emails are in other languages and this tool can be used to translate the messages
for an english speaking to understand and reply to i encourage you to pause the video and run the code
and also try modifying the prompt to see if you can get a different output
now let's hope our customer service agent reply to the customer in their original language so let's say
english speaking customer service agent writes this is a hey there customer warranty does not cover
cleaning expenses for a kitchen because it's your fault that you misuse your blender by forgetting to put on
the lid tough luck see ya not a very polite message but um let's say this is what a customer service agent wants
we are going to specify that the service message is going to be translated to this pirate style so we
want it to be in a polite tone that speaks in english pirate and because we previously created that prompt
template the cool thing is we can now reuse that prompt template and specify that the output style we want
is this service style pirate and the text is this service reply and if we do that
that's the prompt
and if we prompt um chat gpt this is the response it gives us back
ahoy there matey i must kindly inform you that the warranty be not covering the expenses or cleaning your
galley and so on i tough luck farewell me hearty so you might be wondering why are we using prompt
templates instead of you know just an f-string the answer is that as you build sophisticated applications
prompts can be quite long and detailed and so prompt templates are a useful abstraction to help you
reuse good prompts when you can um this is an example of a relatively long prompt to grade a student's
submission for online learning application and a problem like this can be quite long in which you can ask
the lm to first solve the problem and then have the output in a certain format and output in a certain
format and wrapping this in a lang chain prompt makes it easier to reuse a prompt like this also you see
later that lang chain provides prompts for some common operations such as summarization or
question answering or connecting to sql databases or connecting to different apis and so by using some
of lang chain's built-in prompts you can quickly get an application working without needing to
engineer your own prompts one other aspect of lang chain's prompt libraries is that it also supports
output parsing which we'll get to in a minute but when you're building a complex application using an lm
you often instruct the lm to generate its output in a certain format such as using specific keywords
this example on the left illustrates using an lm to carry out something called chain of thought
reasoning using a framework called the react framework but don't worry about the technical details but the
one of the keys of that is that the thought is what the lm is thinking because by giving an lm space to think
it can often get to more accurate conclusions then action as a keyword to carry the specific action
and then observation to show what it learned from that action and so on and if you have a prompt that instructs
the lm to use these specific keywords thought action and observation then this prompt can be coupled with
a parser to extract out the text that has been tagged with these specific keywords and so that together
gives a very nice abstraction to specify the input to an lm and then also have a parser correctly
interpret the output that the lm gives and so with that let's return to see an example of an output
parser using langchain in this example let's take a look at how you can have an lm output json and use
langchain to pause that output and the running example that i'll use will be to extract information from a
product review and format that output in a json format so here's an example of how you would like
the output to be formatted um technically this is a python dictionary where whether or not the product is
as a gift maps the falls the number of days it took deliverer was five and the price value was pretty
affordable so this is one example of a desired output here is an example of um customer review as well as
a template to try to get to that json output so here's a customer review it says this leaf blower is
pretty amazing it has four settings candle blower gender breeze windy city and tornado it arrived in
two days just in time for my wife's anniversary present i think my wife liked it so much she was
speechless so far i've been the only one using it and so on um and here's a review template for the
following text extract the following information specify was this a gift so in this case it would be yes
because this is a gift um and also delivery days how long did it take to deliver it looks like in this
case it arrived in two days and um what's the price value you know slightly more expensive other leaf blowers
and so on so the review template asks the lom to take as input a customer review and extract
these three fields and then format the output as json um with the following keys
all right so here's how you can wrap this in line chain let's import the chat prompt template we'd actually
import to this already earlier so technically this line is redundant but i'll just import it again and
then have the prompt template um created from the review template
up on top and so here's the prompt template
and now similar to our earlier usage of a prompt template let's create the
messages to pass to the openai endpoint create the openai endpoint call that endpoint and then let's print out
the response i encourage you to pause the video and run the code
and there are this it says gif is true delivery days is two and the price value also looks pretty accurate
um but note that if we check the type
of the response this is actually a string so it looks like json and looks like his key value pairs but
it's actually not a dictionary this is just one long string so what i really like to do is go to the
response content and get the value from the gift key which should be true but i run this this should
actually generate an error because well this is actually a string this is not a python dictionary
so let's see how we would use langchain's um parser in order to do this i'm going to import
response schema and structured output parser from langchain and um i'm going to tell it what i wanted
to pause by specifying these response schemas so the gift schema is named gift and here's the description
was the item purchase a gift for someone else uh answer true of yes false if not to unknown and so on
so have a gift schema delivery day schema price value schema and then let's put all three of them
into a list as follows now that i've specified the schema for these um langchain could actually give
you the prompt itself uh by having the output parser tell you what instructions it wants you
to send to the lm so if i were to print format instructions
she has a pretty precise set of instructions for the lm that will cause it to generate an
output that the output parser can process so here's a new review template
and the review template includes the format instructions that langchain generated
and so we can create a prompt from the review template too and then create the messages that will pass
to the open ai endpoint if you want you can take a look at the actual prompt
which gives the instructions to extract
the fields gif delivery days price value here's the text and then here are the formatting instructions
finally if we call the open ai endpoint let's take a look at what response we got
it is now this
and now if we use the output parser that we created
earlier you can then pause this into an output dictionary which if i print looks like this
and notice that this is um of type dictionary not a string which is why i can now extract the value
associated with the key gift and get true or the value associated with delivery days and get two or you
can also um extract the value associated with price value so this is a nifty way to take your lm output and
parse it into a python dictionary to make the output easier to use in downstream processing i encourage you to pause the video and run the code
and so that's it for models prompt and parsers with these tools hopefully you'll be able to
reuse your own prompt templates easily share prompt templates with others that you're collaborating with
even use linechain's built-in prompt templates which as you just saw can often be coupled with an output parser
so that the input prompt to output in a specific format and then the parser pauses that output to store the data in a python dictionary or some other data structure that makes it easy for downstream processing
i hope you find this useful in many of your applications and with that let's go into the next video where
we'll see how lanking can help you build better chat bots or have an lm have more effective chats
by better managing what it remembers from the conversation you've had so far